Register of the Vrangel' collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- ROSSIISKII VOENNYI AGENT V KONSTANTINOPOLE, 1919-1923 (Boxes 96-112)
  - (Group I, File 90)
    - Evacuation of Gallipoli Detachment, 1923
      - Correspondence re evacuation. Includes letters of Lieut.-Gen. G. CHertkov; Esaul V. Ilovaiskii and Col. A. von Lampe, Military Representative of Commander-in-Chief of Russian Armies in Hungary; League of Nations, High Commission for Refugees; Lieut.-Gen. P. Kusonskii, Chief of Staff, Russian Army; Maj.-Gen. Z. Martynov, Commander of Gallipoli contingent; Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, Chief of Staff, Russian Army, typescript and handwritten, October 1922-May (Folder 2-4)
  - (Group I, File 91)
    - Archive of Military Agent in Constantinople
      - Inventory of material from office of the Representative of Commander-in-Chief of the Russian Army to the Allied Command in Constantinople, typescript, September 29, 1921 (Box 102, Folder 5)
      - Material officialy destroyed, includes papers of Gallipoli Detachment, typescript, August-December 1922 (Folder 6)
      - Material transferred into keeping of Representative of the Commander-in-Chief of the Russian Army in Paris, Lieut.- Gen. I. KHolmsen. Includes inventory and correspondence re transfer, typescript, December 1922 January 1923 (Folder 7)
    - Military awards and decorations, correspondence, typescript and handwritten, 1922
      - General, including awards to foreign officials and military personnel, March-December (Folder 8)
      - Award of decoration "Russian Army in Exile, ," November 1921-December, 1920-1921 (Folder 9)
    - Personnel
      - General, typescript and handwritten, September 1921-June 1923 (Folder 10)
      - Replacement of Lieut.-Gen. G. CHertkov by Gen. IU. Romanovskii, miscellaneous material, typescript, June-September 1923 (Folder 11)
      - Visas for agency personnel, includes lists of personnel, typescript, March-October 1922 (Folder 12)
  - (Group I, File, 92, 93)
    - Financial records, typescript and handwritten material
      - General, correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. G. CHertkov with General Staff Headquarters, Sremski Karlovci and Representative of the Commander-in-Chief in Paris. Includes letters of Lieut.-Gen. P. Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. P. Miller, Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmsen, June 1922-August 1923 (Box 102, Folder 13-20)
        Available on microfilm reel 124
    - Financial records, contd.
      - Disbursements to individuals, including charity cases, June 1922-July 1923 (Box 103, Folder 1-2)
      - Gallipoli Detachment and veterans of Gallipoli, June-June 1923 (Folder 3-8)
        Folders 3-7 available on microfilm reel 124; folder 8 on reel 125
      - Invalids, hospitals and charitable organizations, June-July 1923 (Folder 9-10)
        Available on microfilm reel 125
      - Military refugee camps, mostly "Selimie,", January-April 1923 (Folder 11)
  - (Group I, File 94)
    - Military Court of Honor. Files of cases referred to Military Agent, typescript and handwritten material, January-December 1923 (Box 103, Folder 12-15)
  - (Group I, File 95)
    - Gallipoli Detachment, 1923
      - Day-orders, typescript, January-May (Box 103, Folder 16)
      - Martynov, Maj.-Gen. Z., daily reports re condition and activities of detachment, typescript, January-April (Folder 17-18)
      - Statistics re composition of detachment, typescript, January-April (Folder 19)
      - Lists of supplies received from A.R.A., typescript, January-February (Folder 20)
  - (Group I, File 96-97)
    - Business correspondence. Receipts for goods, special disbursements from agencies and individuals and expenditures related to the maintainance of the Military Agent's Office, its Passport-Pass Section (Pasportno-Propusknoe Otdelenie) and the Gallipoli Detachment. Includes correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. G. CHertkov, Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, Lieut.-Gen. P. Kusonskii, M. Girs, A. Neratov, Lieut.-Gen. A. Viazmitinov, Gen. D. Pototskii, Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen, typescript and handwritten material, October 1921-June 1922 (Box 104, Folder 1-11)
  - (Group I, File 98-102)
    - Gallipoli Detachment. Correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. G. CHertkov with G.H.Q. of the Commander-in-Chief and Col. A. von Lampe, Representative of the C.-in-C. in Hungary re evacuation of Gallipoli Detachment. Includes correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. P. Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen. Also includes correspondence with Maj.-Gen. Z. Martynov re internal affairs and condition of Gallipoli Detachment; relations with Allies; negotiations with A.R.A. and League of Nations re supply and feeding of detachment; transfer of invalids, women and children to Constantinople (Selimie Camp) (File 100-102); plans for establishing agricultural colony and other commercial enterprises (File 101); correspondence between Baron P. Vrangel' and Fridtjof Nansen (File 101); lists of personnel with statistics re marital status, age, profession and health (File 98-101), typescript and handwritten material
      - (Group I, File 98), January-June 1923 (Box 104, Folder 12-17)
        Available on microfilm reel 126
      - (Group I, File 99), May-October 1922 (Folder 18-19)
      - Group I, File 99), contd., May-October 1922 (Box 105, Folder 1-4)
      - Group I, File 100), May-July 1922 (Folder 5-9)
      - (Group I, File 101), July-September 1922 (Folder 10-15)
        Folders 10-11 available on microfilm reel 126; folders 12-15 on reel 127
      - (Group I, File 102), September-December 1922 (Box 106, Folder 1-3)
        Available on microfilm reel 127
  - (Group I, File 103)
    - Evacuation of military refugees including Gallipoli Detachment from Constantinople (Selimie Camp) to Serbia. Correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. G. CHertkov with: G.H.Q. of Commander-in-Chief, including Lieut.-Gen. P. Kusonskii and Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller; miscellaneous Russian social organizations; A.R.A. and League of Nations, High Commission for Refugees, Constantinople. Also includes lists of evacuees and individual documents granted by Military Agent, typescript and handwritten material, January-May, 1923 (Box 106, Folder 4-9)
      Folders 4-7 available on microfilm reel 127; folders 8-9 on reel 128
  - (Group I, File 104)
    - Correspondence, officially classified as secret, typescript unless otherwise indicated, 1922
      - Chertkov, Lieut.-Gen. G.
        - Outgoing
          - General, office, September 8-October 24 (Box 106, Folder 10)
            Available on microfilm reel 128
          - Il'in, S., September 20-December 23 (Folder 11)
          - Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. P., September 9-December 23 (Folder 12)
          - Martynov, Maj.-Gen. Z., September 28-October 19 (Folder 13)
          - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., September 6-December 23 (Folder 14)
          - Neratov, A., September 28 (Folder 15)
          - Lampe, Col. A. von, December 23 (Folder 16)
          - Vrangel', Baron P., October 19 (Folder 17)
        - Incoming
          - Gerua, Lieut.-Gen. A., September 23 (Folder 18)
          - Il'in, S., November 24, 1921, October 17-November 21 (Folder 19)
          - Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. P., September 9-December 15 (Folder 20)
          - Lampe, Col. A. von, October 19-November 10 (Folder 21)
          - Martynov, Maj.-Gen. Z., holograph, April 30 (Folder 22)
          - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., holograph, October 5, 27 (Folder 23)
          - Vrangel', Baron P., September 9 (Folder 24)
      - Johnson, J.J.
        - Burnier (?), Capt., United Nations High Commission for Russian Refugees in Constantinople, August 24 (Folder 25)
        - Nansen, Fridthof, August 28 (Folder 26)
      - Krasnov, Gen. P., open letter to Don Cossacks, September 19 (Folder 27)
      - Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. P.
        - KHolmnsen, Lieut.-Gen. I., December 7 (Folder 28)
        - Tiesenhausen, Baron A., December 8 (Folder 29)
      - Stal', Baron (on behalf of Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaevich) to Baron P. Vrangel', December 8, 1922 (Folder 30)
      - Vrangel', Baron P.
        - Markov, N., October 22 (Folder 31)
        - Russian Military Agents and Representatives, Yacht "Lucullus", May 10, 1921 (Folder 32)
        - Trepov, A., and A. Trepov, N. Markov, N. SHebeko, N. CHebyshev, M. Goremykin, August 30, October 28 (Folder 33)
    - Reports, officially classified as secret, typescript, 1922
      - General. Soviet activity in Constantinople, particularly of Vneshtorg representative, G. Zolotarev, December 8 (Box 107, Folder 1)
      - Official communiques of G.H.Q. signed Lieut.-Gen. Arkhangel'skii and Lieut.-Gen. P. Kusonskii, includes information re: fate of Petrogradskaia Ssudnaia Kazna, condition of army units in exile; Bolshevik efforts to repatriate exiles; Russian military exiles in Bulgaria, September-October (Folder 2)
      - Il'in, S., "Svodka informatsionnykh soobshchenii," typescript, No., 6, 8, 9, August-September (Folder 3)
      - Pototskii, Maj.-Gen. D., Russian Military Agent in Denmark, miscellaneous typescript reports re foreign policy of Soviet Union, Red Army, activity of Soviet agents abroad, August 22-October 12 (Folder 4)
      - Leontiev, Maj.-Gen. M., Russian Military Agent in Czechoslovakia, summaries of Soviet press, mimeograph, April-November (Folder 5)
    - "Dame Noire," typescript report and newspaper clippings re trial, July 18-22 (Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous material from office of Military Agent in Turkey, including intelligence reports re individuals, typescript, November-December (Folder 7)
  - (Group I, File 105)
    - Correspondence officially classified as secret, typescript unless otherwise indicated, 1922
      - Chertkov, Lieut.-Gen. G.
        - Outgoing
          - General, office, May-August (Box 107, Folder 8)
          - Il'in, S., August 2-26 (Folder 9)
          - Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. P., June 22-August 21 (Folder 10)
          - Martynov, Maj.-Gen. Z., Also includes covering letter to A. Neratov, August 1-2 (Folder 11)
            Available on microfilm reel 129
          - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., June 20 (Folder 12)
        - Incoming
          - Il'in, S., August 5-September 4 (Folder 13)
          - Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. P., July 13-August 24 (Folder 14)
          - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., May 29-June 19 (Folder 15)
          - Pototskii, Maj.-Gen. D.,includes information re G. Zolotarev, May 13-June 19 (Folder 16)
      - Donskoi Kadetskii Korpus, miscellaneous correspondence re evacuation, typescript and holograph, May 31-June 14 (Folder 17)
      - Kirill Vladimirovich, Grand Duke of Russia, address to Russian Army, August 1922 (Folder 18)
      - Kolomeitsev, A., secretary, Soiuz vozvrashcheniia na Rodinu to G. Zolotarev, representative of Vneshtorg R.S.F.S.R. v Konstantinopole, typescript copy, May 30 (Folder 19)
      - Leontiev, Maj.-Gen. M. to S. Il'in, July 25-29 (Folder 20)
      - Rosiisskaia Diplomaticheskaia Missiia v Konstantinopole, miscellaneous correspondence, May-June (Folder 21)
      - Vrangel', Baron P. to Bulgarian Council of Ministers, copies of letter and telegram, See also Group I, File 89, May 18, 1922 (Folder 22)
    - Reports, typescript, 1922
      - General
        - Bulgaria. Includes intelligence agent's report to Osobyi Otdel SHtaba Glavnokomanduiushchago, May 16 (Folder 23)
        - League of Nations, High Commission for Russian (Folder 24)
        - Refugees in Constantinople, intelligence report of Pasportno-Propusknoe Otdelenie, June 25
        - "Dogovor Germanii s Sovetskoi Ukrainskoi Respublikoi," office of Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent v Konstantinopole, May 6 (Folder 25)
        - Vneshtorg R.S.F.S.R. v Konstantinopole and Zakavkazskii Obvneshtorg, intelligence report and lists of employees, June 23 (Folder 26)
      - Gerua, Lieut.-Gen. A., Russian Military Agent in Rumania, "Politicheskoe polozhenie v Rumynii v nachale goda", 1922 (Folder 27)
      - Leontiev, Maj.-Gen. M., Russian Military Agent in Czechoslovakia
        - Public opinion in Soviet Union from interviews with recent emigres, June 23 (Folder 28)
        - Summaries of Soviet and European press, mimeograph, May-August (Folder 29)
      - Pototskii, Maj.-Gen. D., Russian Military Agent in Denmark. Includes "Svodka raznykh svedenii," No. 7, 8,; "O sovetskoi missii v Stokgol'me," March 25, March-May (Folder 30)
      - Vrangel', Baron P., report re his visit to Russian Army troops in Belgrade area, August 1922? (Folder 31)
    - Pasportnoe-Propusknoe Otdelenie pri Voennom Agente v Turtsii, report re its organization and activities; reports on individuals, July (Folder 32)
  - (Group I, File 106)
    - Correspondence officially classified as secret, typescript unless otherwise indicated, 1923
      - Boy Scouts, miscellaneous correspondence re internal organization. Includes material re I. Klochko, N. Kotliarevskii, Lieut.-Gen. Nevodovskii and Col. O. Pantiukhov, November 8, 1922-February 3, 1923 (Box 107, Folder 33)
      - CHertkov, Lieut.-Gen. G.
        - Outgoing
          - General, office, August 15-March 7 (Folder 34)
          - Arkhangel'skii, P., March 21 (Folder 35)
          - Il'in, S., January 24-May 30 (Folder 36)
          - Klimovich, Lieut.-Gen. E., January 2-9 (Folder 37)
          - Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. P.
            - re evacuation of refugees to Serbia, includes copy of report by Gen. Baratov, official letter of authorization from Serbian Ministry of Foreign Affairs and list of individuals receiving A.R.A. rations, January 4 (Folder 38)
            - March 21 includes correspondence re Soiuz Invalidov, January 9-March 24 (Folder 39)
          - Martynov, Maj.-Gen. Z., Includes copies of letters from subordinate officers re removal of Gen. Fitselaurov, January 22-26 (Folder 40)
          - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., March 1, includes copy of report of unidentified foreign mission in Moscow, January 9-March 28 (Folder 41)
          - N.B., surname unknown to A.A. and N.N., re monarchism, January 17 (Folder 42)
          - Viazmitinov, Lieut.-Gen. A., January 9 (Folder 43)
        - Incoming
          - Il'in, S., Jan 30 (Box 108, Folder 1)
          - Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. P., January 31-April 19 (Folder 2)
          - Martynov, Maj.-Gen. Z., March 26 (Folder 3)
          - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., February 20-28 (Folder 4)
          - Polunin, A., January 3 (Folder 5)
          - Pototskii, Maj.-Gen. S., January 16 (Folder 6)
        - Pelle (Glavkom), excerpt from letter re activity of Soviet agent SHcheglov in Bulgaria, November 1922 (Folder 7)
    - Reports, typescript, 1923
      - Internal report re reorganization of intelligence work of Military Agent's office, January 2-February 5 (Folder 8)
      - Official communiques of G.H.Q., some signed Lieut.-Gen. P. Kusonskii, January 3-March 17 (Folder 9)
      - "Protokol soveshchaniia starshikh nachak'nikov Russkoi armii i predstavitelei Smetno-Rasporiaditel'noi Komissii i Finansovo-Kontrol'nago Komitata pri Glavnokomanduiushchem,", January 27 (Folder 10)
      - Il'in, S., "Svodka informatsionnykh svedenii," No. 12, Feb, 27, 1922 (Folder 11)
    - Russkii Natsional'nyi Komitet v Parizhe: excerpt from resolution,; New Year's address to Russian Army, December 11, 1922 (Folder 12)
  - (Group I, File 107)
    - Correspondence, officially classified as secret, typescript, unless otherwise indicated, April-November 1923
      - CHertkov, Lieut.-Gen. G.
        - Outgoing
          - General, office, April 20-June 5 (Box 108, Folder 13)
          - Chairman, Court of Honor, April 10 (Folder 14)
          - Abramov, F., Includes material re Gen. Raukh, August 12-22 (Folder 15)
          - Baratov, Gen. N., May 29 (Folder 16)
          - Il'in, S., April 4-May 30 (Folder 17)
          - Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. P., April 6-May 31 (Folder 18)
          - Martynov, Maj.-Gen. Z., April 4-18 (Folder 19)
          - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., April 3 includes copy of Soviet radiogram. April 18 includes letter of Henri Reymond, League of Nations, Haut Commissariat pour les Réfugiés Russes and S. Lawford Childs, High Commission For Refugees in Constantinople, April 3-25 (Folder 20)
          - Petr Grigorievich, April 5 (Folder 21)
        - Incoming
          - Baratov, Gen. N., April 23 (Folder 22)
          - Klimovich, Lieut.-Gen. E., includes copy of Serbian intelligence report, July 7-14 (Folder 23)
          - Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. P., April 10 (Folder 24)
          - Martynov, Maj.-Gen. Z., October 28, 1922-January 1, 1923 (Folder 25)
          - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., June 26
      - Conwall, John, G.H.Q., British Forces in Turkey to Lieut.-Gen. G. CHertkov, June 15, 1923 (Folder 26)
      - Frolov, Col. V. to F. Abramov, A. Stanislavskii and Lieut.-Gen. G. CHertkov, re replacement of Military Agent and Gen. Raukh affair, August 2-16 (Folder 27)
        Available on microfilm reel 130
      - Vrangel', Baron P. to M. Girs, Senior Russian Diplomatic Representative abroad, June 23 (Folder 28)
    - Reports, typescript, 1923
      - Official communiques, signed Lieut.-Gen. P. Kusonskii, includes material re monarchism, May 10-12 (Folder 29)
      - Pototskii, Maj.-Gen. D., Russian Military Agent in Denmark. Includes material re A.R.A. in Soviet Union, January 16 (Folder 30)
    - Addresses, typescript, 1923
      - Soiuz russkikh ofitserov Armii i Flota (Turkish and Bulgarian section) to Grand Duke Kirill Vladimirovich (?), September 1922 (Folder 31)
      - Sovet ob"edinennykh ofitserskikh obshchestv (Sremski Karlovci) to Prince Dondukov-Iz"edinov, chairman Monarkhicheskoe Ob"edinenie, September 1922 (Folder 32)
      - "Ot imeni Ego Imperatorskago Vysochestva Avgusteishago Bliustitelia Gosudareva Prestola Velikago Kniazia Kirilla Vladimirovicha...," printed copy, September 2, 1922 (Folder 33)
  - (Group I, File 108)
    - Correspondence re Russian refugees, mostly of Lieut.-Gen. G. CHertkov, 1922
      - Evacuation of Russian refugees from Constantinople to Serbia. Includes correspondence with Lieut.-Gen. P. Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, A. Neratov, Soiuz Invalidov, Russkii Komitet, Rossiiskoe Obshchestvo Krasnago Kresta; lists of evacuees; sample registration forms, typescript and handwritten, October 20-December 20 (Box 108, Folder 34-35)
      - Russian officers expelled from Bulgaria, maintainance and evacuation to Serbia, typescript, May 26-December 13 (Folder 36-37)
  - (Group I, File 109)
    - Investigation into murder of Lieut-Gen. I. Romanovskii, April 1920
      - Notice, Allied police, printed copy (Box 108, Folder 38)
      - Physical evidence including doctor's report, typescript and handwritten material (Folder 39)
      - Protocols, interrogation of eye-witnesses. Includes English translations, typescript and handwritten material (Folder 40)
      - Clipping, Armianskiia Posledniia Novosti, includes Russian translation, printed copy (Folder 41)
  - (Group I, File 110)
    - Criminal investigations under jurisdiction of Russian Military Agent in Constantinople, typescript and handwritten material, 1920-1921 (Box 109, Folder 1-7)
      Folders 1-2 available on microfilm reel 130; folders 3-7 on reel 131
  - (Group I, File 112)
    - List of military personnel returning to the Soviet Union, typescript, February 1, 1923 (Box 109, Folder 8)
      Available on microfilm reel 131
    - Obshchestvo Gallipoliitsev, statutes, typescript, November 29, 1921 (Folder 9)
    - Obshchestvo ofitserov General'nago SHtaba, protocol of meeting, typescript, June 2, 1923 (Folder 10)
    - Rossiiskii Voennyi Agent, official announcement re regulations for evacuation of military personnel, typescript and printed copies, undated (Folder 11)
    - Sanitarnaia CHast' voennykh kontingentov Russkoi Armii, report re activities, typescript, January 18, 1923 (Folder 12)
    - Soiuz Russkikh Invalidov, miscellaneous material, including correspondence, reports, resolutions, typescript and handwritten, November 6, 1922-March 27, 1923 (Folder 13)
    - Sovet Soiuzov byvshikh russkikh voinov v Turtsii
      - Correspondence, miscellaneous, October 20, 1922-March 14, 1923 (Folder 14)
      - Minutes of meetings, typescript
        - 1-12, July 20-September 8, 1921 (Folder 15)
        - 13-31, September 21, 1921-January 27, 1922 (Folder 16)
        - 33-47, February 10-May 26, 1922 (Folder 17)
        - 48-68, June 2-October 10, 1922 (Folder 18)
      - Ekonomicheskoe obshchestvo Soveta Soiuzov, financial reports, typescript, July 1-October 1, 1922 (Folder 19)
  - (Group I, File 113)
    - Intelligence reports, typescript and handwritten, 1921
      - General. Includes material re political conditions and diplomatic activity of England, France, Germany, Iran, Italy, Japan, U.S. and Turkey; relations of European and other powers to anti-Bolshevik cause; Russian-language press abroad and its influence on European public opinion; activities of Russian emigre groups abroad; conditions in the Soviet Union, April 1920-September (Box 109, Folder 20-22)
    - Intelligence reports, contd.
      - Individuals and organizations under investigation for pro-Bolshevik and criminal activity, April 1920-November (Box 110, Folder 1-2)
        Available on microfilm reel 132
  - (Group I, File 114)
    - Intelligence reports
      - General, handwritten and typescript, December 1920-September 1921 (Box 110, Folder 3)
      - International situation; relations of Russian Army with European powers and the Balkans; relations with Allied authorities in Constantinople, typescript, 1921, November 1920-November (Folder 4)
    - Political and social organizations of emigre community
      - Komitet po bor'be s pogromami na Ukraine, intelligence reports, typescript, March-June 1921 (Folder 5)
      - Officer's organizations, intelligence report, typescript, September 1921 (Folder 6)
      - Partiia sotsialistov-revoliutsionerov, intelligence reports, typescript and handwritten, October 1920-December 1921 (Folder 7)
      - Politicheskoe Ob"edinenie, intelligence report, typescript, January 2, 1920 (Folder 8)
      - Vserossiiskii Zemskii Soiuz and Ob"edinenie Rossiiskikh Zemskikh i Gorodskikh Deiatelei. Miscellaneous material including correspondence and newspaper clippings, typescript, handwritten and printed matter, June-December 1921 (Folder 9)
    - Separatist movements, typescript
      - Caucasus, intelligence reports, 1921
        - Komitet Azerbaidzhanskago Gorskago Otriada, September (Folder 10)
        - Pravitel'stvo Tersko-Dagestanskago Kraia, October (Folder 11)
      - Kuban' Cossacks
        - General, miscellaneous material, typescript and printed matter including IUzhnoe Slovo, October 1919-March 1920 (Folder 12)
        - Intelligence reports, mostly re Gen. SHkuro, typescript, April-October 1921 (Folder 13)
      - Ukraine
        - Miscellaneous material, typescript and printed matter including Sovremennoe Slovo and Velikaia Rossiia, September 1919-June 1920 (Folder 14)
        - Ukrainskii Natsional'nyi Komitet, intelligence reports, typescript, April-December 1921 (Folder 15)
  - (Group I, File 115)
    - Intelligence reports, correspondence and other miscellaneous material
      - General
        - CHeka, composition of Petrograd, Kiev and Kamenets-Podol'skii committees, typescript, June-July 1921 (Box 110, Folder 16)
        - Soviet Union, including Byelorussia and Caucasus, typescript, March-October, 1921 (Folder 17)
      - Activity of Soviet government, the III Communist International and other Soviet supported organizations in Europe, typescript unless otherwise indicated, 1921
        - General, includes reports re Soviet agents and individuals under investigation, March-October (Folder 18)
        - Communist International, miscellaneous material re its organization in Europe. Includes diagram, February (Folder 19)